Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and we're
talking about the stars today.
That's right. Today we're
going to talk about a very
popular subject, many people
believe in the horoscope.
So horoscope is basically
a system, very old system of
determining your future and
describing your personality.
And so it all depends on when you
were born and where you were born.
So what stars were in the
sky when you were born?
That's right. So basically, as many
of you may know, there are 12 signs.
And we're going to
talk about a couple of
them and a little bit
more about horoscopes.
And I don't know, I guess it's kind of
like a branch of science or pseudo science.
Yeah, I don't think there's
much testing that's going on, but
it's definitely something
that a lot of people believe in.
So let's take a listen
to today's dialogue and
we'll be back in a moment
to talk more about it.
Hey, Lydia, what are you reading?
I'm looking at my horoscope for this month.
My outlook is very positive.
It says that I should take
a vacation to someplace
exotic and that I will have
a passionate summer fling.
What are you talking about?
Let me see that.
What are horoscopes?
It's a prediction of your month
based on your zodiac sign.
You have a different sign for the
month and date you were born in.
I was born on April 15th, so I'm an Aries.
When were you born?
January 5th.
Let's see.
You're a Capricorn.
It says that you'll be feeling
stress at work, but you
could see new exciting
developments in your love life.
Looks like we'll both
have interesting summers.
That's bogus.
I don't feel any stress at work and
my love life is practically non-existent.
This zodiac stuff is all
a bunch of nonsense.
No, it's not. Your astrology sign can
tell you a lot about your personality.
See? It says that an Aries is
energetic and loves to socialize.
Well, you certainly
match those criteria, but
they're so broad they
could apply to anyone.
What does it say about me?
A Capricorn is
serious-minded and practical.
She likes to do things
in conventional ways.
That sounds just like you.
Alright, we're back.
So a very interesting dialogue
between these two girls talking about
one of them believing in the
horoscope and the other one doesn't.
But they mentioned a
lot of interesting things,
so we're going to have
two language takeaways.
Today, let's start with
language takeaway part one.
Language takeaway.
Alright, so one of the most
common things you'll hear
when we talk about the
horoscope in English is an outlook.
And an outlook can be positive or negative.
So what exactly is an outlook?
Well, if you notice Lydia said,
my outlook is very positive.
So basically she's
talking about her future.
So the way that she sees
the future or the way that
the horoscope talks about
the future is a positive one.
So you could say, you know those
eight balls, they're black and they
have like a message and you
shake it and it gives you a message.
You ask a question.
You ask a question that
says outlook positive.
That's right.
Outlook negative.
That means in your near future,
things will either be positive or negative.
So I guess you can apply it
for example to a company,
you say that a company
has a positive outlook.
Or even a person, you know,
he's very positive person.
So he has a positive outlook.
He thinks good things are going to happen.
Okay, very good.
So talking about horoscopes, obviously
we must mention the 12 zodiac signs.
Okay, so each month has its own
sign and they're not exactly the months.
They're a little bit different.
But each sign is kind
of an animal or a symbol.
That's right.
So for example, a lot of August
is part of the Leo sign in English.
So that's the lion.
And so the lion is the animal, the zodiac.
So the zodiac sign is one of these signs.
Like Leo is one of the zodiac signs.
And I guess the all 12 signs are
considered the zodiac or the horoscope.
Exactly.
And you can actually talk about
the zodiac in terms of other cultures.
There is a Chinese zodiac.
So we could say it's the year of the horse.
But that's a little bit
different from what we're
talking about here with
the Western horoscope.
Okay, very good.
So all of this actually comes
down to the, as we say,
the pseudoscience or the
branch called astrology.
Astrology.
So this is a very hard
word for some people to
remember because they
want to say astronomy.
But it's different.
Astronomy is the
scientific study of the
skies, the stars,
planets, things like that.
Astrology is different.
It's what we're talking
about here, the horoscope.
And reading the stars to understand
what our personal futures will hold for us.
That's right.
So astronomy is an exact science
part of, I guess, a physics where you
talk about the stars or the composition
of the stars and their movements.
Whereas in astrology, we're
talking about zodiacs and horoscopes
and basically what star was
in the sky when you were born.
But in a different way,
it's not very scientific.
That's right.
So astrology is normally what you
would see in the newspaper when
you're trying to find your
horoscope, astrology or horoscope.
And actually every time you read the
newspaper, if you look up your zodiac sign, it
makes a prediction about your day or your
week or maybe even sometimes a month or year.
That's right.
And so prediction is basically a
guess about what will happen for you.
That's right.
So many times you see that the
horoscope will say finances are in trouble.
Be careful with how you spend your money.
So they're making a prediction
that in the future maybe
you're going to have money
problems so you have to be careful.
Exactly.
Or in the dialogue, you will
have a passionate summer fling.
This is a prediction.
It has not yet happened.
It will happen.
That's right.
A prediction.
So now talking a little bit
more about the zodiac signs that
we saw in the dialogue, we
mentioned two Aries and Capricorn.
So a lot of people who believe in astrology
say that astrological signs are broken up.
They're divided into
different kinds of signs.
We have water signs, air
signs, earth signs and fire signs.
So one of the famous
fire signs is Aries, right?
Aries.
It's like the God of War
in the Greek mythology.
That's right.
And so it's pronounced Aries Aries.
A-R-I-E-S Aries, that's right.
And the other one is a Capricorn.
Capricorn.
So that's like a goat.
Yeah, it's kind of like a ram.
A ram.
So an earth sign.
That's right.
So there are 12, these
are just two of them.
And obviously there
are a lot more, I guess,
off the top of my head,
we have Taurus or Leo.
There's also a Scorpio.
Sagittarius.
Gemini.
Gemini, which are like twins, twin people.
There's Pisces.
Virgo.
Virgo the Virgin.
And I don't know if we're missing anything.
I can't think now.
We'll have to talk about it at
the very end of today's lesson.
But we actually have some interesting
things to talk about in a minute here.
We have to talk about the personality
characteristics that are common
when you're talking
about different zodiac signs.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, so before we get to that,
let's listen to our dialogue again.
[MUSIC] Hey, Lydia.
What are you reading?
I'm looking at my horoscope for this month.
My outlook is very positive.
It says that I should take a
vacation to someplace exotic
and that I will have a
passionate summer fling.
What are you talking about?
Let me see that.
What are horoscopes?
It's a prediction of your month
based on your zodiac sign.
You have a different sign for the
month and date you were born in.
I was born on April 15th, so I'm in Aries.
When were you born?
January 5th.
Let's see.
You're a Capricorn.
It says that you'll be
feeling stress at work,
but you could see new exciting
developments in your love life.
Looks like we'll both
have interesting summers.
That's bogus.
I don't feel any stress at work, and
my love life is practically non-existent.
This zodiac stuff is all
a bunch of nonsense.
No, it's not.
Your astrology sign can tell
you a lot about your personality.
See?
It says that an Aries is
energetic and loves to socialize.
Well, you certainly match those criteria,
but they're so broad they
could apply to anyone.
What does it say about me?
A Capricorn is seriously
minded and practical.
She likes to do things
in conventional ways.
That sounds just like you.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look at these
personality traits on language.
Take away part two.
Language takeaway.
All right, so one of the great words that
we heard in today's dialogue was exotic.
Okay, and this is not
necessarily describing a
person, but usually
things or cloves or places.
And in this instance, it
was some place, exotic.
That's right.
What's an exotic place?
It's basically a place that's very unique,
and I guess it's kind of not
common to go there or to find.
For example, many
people talk about an exotic
getaway going to the
jungle because it's so exotic.
You have so many strange animals and
plants, and everything is so unfamiliar.
All right, so in my
mind, Tahiti is very exotic.
All right, it's full of jungle,
and there's also beaches,
and it's very unusual for someone who's
from America because it's just so far away.
That's right, exotic.
So someone can also
have an exotic personality
because maybe they're
a little bit strange,
or not strange, but not
so common, maybe unique.
Yeah, although exotic
is usually kind of a
sexy thing when you're
talking about people.
That's right.
That's very exotic. That means she
doesn't look like everybody else here.
That's right.
But another adjective
to describe someone's
personality is somebody
that's very energetic.
All right, so energetic
sounds like the word energy.
That's because they're related.
So someone who's
energetic has lots of energy.
He or she likes to do a lot of
things and wants to always go places.
You know the energetic
person at your office.
They always drink coffee.
That's right.
Maybe they make everyone
else really tired this thing to do.
That's right.
And actually a person that's
energetic usually also loves to socialize.
That's right.
So loves to means they
like to, but they like it a lot.
But to socialize means
to talk to other people
or to go to parties or
to meet new people.
So if it's a verb to socialize
means to talk to people,
to meet people, to greet people, you
love to have contact with other people.
So yeah, you're right, very, very
common for people who are energetic.
Okay.
And what about someone that's practical?
What does that like?
Someone who's practical
does a lot of things.
Someone who's practical always
comes to their activities prepared.
So in my car, I'm very practical.
I have extra water and a spare tire.
But you can also say,
I'm a very practical person.
I like to do things that I can achieve
as opposed to someone
who always wants to do things
that they can't really achieve.
Okay.
So a practical person
is usually very realistic
and very down to earth.
Maybe someone that's
practical if they're going on a trip
that'll only take what's necessary,
not more than they need.
Yeah, exactly.
Let me give you a good example.
I like to go hiking.
And sometimes I see women
who have not made very
practical decisions
about the shoes they wear.
So I like to wear hiking boots.
These are very practical.
Wearing high heels on a
mountain is not very practical.
That's right.
Okay.
Very good.
Now, we also mentioned that
a Capricorn is serious-minded
and conventional in many ways.
Someone who's serious-minded
maybe doesn't like to have fun
and go out and do things that are silly.
Someone who's serious-minded
is usually very practical, I think,
and really has a goal,
wants to achieve that goal.
You know, no time to be
silly, no time to make jokes.
So it doesn't necessarily
mean that the person is boring,
but they're just very,
as you said, practical.
Okay.
And what about that Capricorn also
likes to do things in conventional ways?
All right.
So conventional means doing
something in a conventional way
means that you're doing
it in a traditional way.
So this is a thing we've always done.
We've always done it in this way.
And I'm going to
continue to do it in this way.
Okay.
So the opposite is unconventional.
That means doing things in new
ways, doing things with your imagination.
And so something that's very
conventional is something that, you know,
has been established and we're just
going to continue doing it that way.
So for example, someone
that gets married in a church
is the conventional way, but someone
that gets married while skydiving
is very unconventional.
That's right.
Unconventional.
Oh, absolutely.
Very good.
So a lot of great vocab here.
Why don't we listen to
our dialogue one last time
and we'll be back to talk
with you a little bit more.
Hey, Lydia.
What are you reading?
I'm looking at my horoscope for this month.
My outlook is very positive.
It says that I should take a
vacation to some place exotic
and that I will have a
passionate summer fling.
What are you talking about?
Let me see that.
What are horoscopes?
It's a prediction of your month
based on your zodiac sign.
You have a different sign for the
month and date you were born in.
I was born on April 15th, so I'm in Aries.
When were you born?
January 5th.
Let's see.
You're a Capricorn.
It says that you'll be
feeling stress at work,
but you could see new exciting
developments in your love life.
Looks like we'll both
have interesting summers.
That's bogus.
I don't feel any stress at work, and
my love life is practically non-existent.
This zodiac stuff is all
a bunch of nonsense.
No, it's not.
Your astrology sign can tell
you a lot about your personality.
See, it says that an Aries is
energetic and loves to socialize.
Well, you certainly match those criteria,
but they're so broad they
could apply to anyone.
What does it say about me?
A Capricorn is
serious-minded and practical.
She likes to do things
in conventional ways.
That sounds just like you.
All right, so talk about the
horoscopes, which sign are you?
I'm a Leo, which is actually, I
don't believe in the horoscope,
but I have to say, every time someone
tells me about Leo's, Leo the lion, right?
I agree with most of their
descriptions of my personality.
So, outspoken, loves to socialize.
Very opinionated, which
means I have an opinion
and I don't like to listen to
other people, loves to argue.
Very loud.
So, these are all
qualities that I think I have
and some of them are bad, some of
them are good, but that's the way it is.
But you don't really believe in what magazines
or newspapers say about your outlook.
Nah, the predictions are usually just
basic guesses, but what about you?
What's your sign?
I am a Taurus, so I was born in May.
A bull.
A bull, yes.
So, I'm very stubborn and very strong.
I don't really know what all the
characteristics about the Taurus are.
A opinionated?
A opinionated.
I know that's stronger.
Yeah, exactly.
Doesn't like to be corrected.
Are you describing Taurus
or are you describing me?
Both.
All right, so, it's
actually very interesting.
I think in many ways,
sometimes the glove does fit
and someone's zodiac sign
describes them very well,
again, maybe like the dialogue
says, they are very broad
descriptions that basically
any person can relate to.
Absolutely, I think that
that's one of the tricks
to horoscopes or to
predicting someone's future.
You tell them enough very vague things
that maybe some of them
will fit and some of them won't.
That's right.
But I'm very curious
to hear about you guys.
What are your signs?
What's your sign?
That means what's your zodiac sign?
That's right.
Maybe also a very common date question.
People say, oh, what's your sign?
Or a pickup line?
Hey, baby, what's your sign?
To see if you're compatible, right?
Right.
So let us know.
We're not trying to pick you up.
We're just curious.
You'll find a lot of the
words for the zodiac in
today's lesson on our
website, www.EnglishPod.com.
We'll see you guys there.
Bye.